Harold Christy Schwalen papers, 1896-1967 (bulk 1919-1965)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Subgroup VI: Supplemental papers and photographs
  - Series IXXX: Miscellaneous studies, 1921-
    - Seismic refraction tests. (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - soil surveys in Arizona. 1917-1936 (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - Head gates. (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - Water measurement devices. (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - Water service statistics. (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - Well-drilling specs and bid forms. (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - Well drilling and pump equipment. (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - Series XXX: Photographs, 1919-1966
    Photographs are mainly of floods, erosion, pumping equipment, drilling rigs, concrete pipe construction, dams, irrigation projects, and adobe construction. There are many duplicates and these have been left in original order under a subject or geographical area.
    - T11S/R9E (Asarco Concentrator). 1962 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - T11S/R10E (Trico Powerhouse). 1959-1965 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - T11S/R11E (Avra Valley). 1954-1955, 1962 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - T11S/R14E (Pusch Ridge). 1953 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - T12S/R1E (La Ventana). (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - T12S/R10E (Wong well). 1957-1968 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - T12S/R11E (Wong well). 1964 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - T12S/R12E (Santa Cruz bank control). 1954-1965 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - T12S/R13E (Canada del Oro). 1950-1964 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - T12S/R14E (Pusch Ridge). 1953-1958 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - T12S/R18E (San Pedro River). 1962-1964 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - T12S/R19E (San Pedro River). 1962-1966 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - T13S/R10E (Anway well). 1953 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - T13S/R11E (Avra Valley). 1954 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - T13S/R13E (Oracle,Roger roads). 1952-1960 (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - T13S/R14E (Gravel pits at Dodge Bridge). 1959-1960 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - T13S/R14E (Rillito Creek). 1959-1967 (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - T13S/R14E (Ventana Wash and Canyon). 1958 (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - T13S/R14E (Sprinklers, pumps). 1956 (Box 46, Folder 19)
    - T13S/R15E (Rillito and Tanque Verde wash). 1954-1956 (Box 46, Folder 20)
    - T13S/R19E (San Pedro and Cascabel). 1962 (Box 46, Folder 21)
    - T14S/R11E (Tucson Mtn. Park). (Box 46, Folder 22)
    - T14S/R13E (Ajo Road bridge). 1967 (Box 46, Folder 23)
    - T14S/R14E (Aggie Building). 1965 (Box 46, Folder 24)
    - T14S/R15E (Atterbury Reservoir). 1954-1962 (Box 46, Folder 25)
    - T14S/R16E (Converse well). 1954-1956 (Box 46, Folder 26)
    - T14S/R20E (San Pedro River Valley). 1962-1965 (Box 46, Folder 27)
    - T15S/R10-11E (Avra Valley). 1953 (Box 46, Folder 28)
    - T15S/R13E (San Xavier Mission). 1952-1956 (Box 46, Folder 29)
    - T15S/R16E (Pantano Wash). 1954 (Box 46, Folder 30)
    - T15S/R20E (Little Dragoon Damsite). 1962 (Box 46, Folder 31)
    - T16S/R10E (King, William stock well). 1962 (Box 46, Folder 32)
    - T16S/R13E (Santa Cruz Basin). 1956 (Box 46, Folder 33)
    - T16S/R14E (Floods and Erosion control). 1950, 1964, 1966, 1968 (Box 46, Folder 34)
    - T16S/R14E (Santa Cruz River flood damage). (Box 46, Folder 35)
    - T17S/R13E (Pima Pit). 1950-1966 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - T17S/R14E (Sahuarito). 1950-1967 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - T18S/R13E (Continental). 1965 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - T18S/R13E (Morrison well, Continental). (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - T19S/R9E (Wells and pumps). 1968 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - T19S/R13E (Santa Cruz flood at Continental Ranch). 1950-1968 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - T20S/R13E (Tubac). 1967 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - T23S/R14E (Santa Cruz River at Patagonia and Nogales). (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - T16S/R16E (Cienega and Pantano dams). 1959 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - T16S/R19-20E (San Pedro River). 1962-1963 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - T22S/R13E (Wells and pumps). 1962 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - T2N/R1W (Goodyear Well). (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - A Mountain. 1935 (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Altar valley. 1951 (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Avra valley pumping plant. 1947 (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Bartlett Dam. (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Casa Grande farm, pipe laying. 1927 (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - Clifton. (Box 47, Folder 18)
    - Continental. (Box 47, Folder 19)
    - Cotton research farm. (Box 47, Folder 20)
    - Curtis Dam. 1933 (Box 47, Folder 21)
    - Del Rio Springs. (Box 47, Folder 22)
    - Flowing wells. (Box 47, Folder 23)
    - Goodyear Citrus Nursery. 1930 (Box 47, Folder 24)
    - Little Chino Valley, not identified. (Box 47, Folder 25)
    - Little Chino Valley, Aiken well. 1940, 1965 (Box 47, Folder 26)
    - Little Chino Valley, Pumping plant. 1948 (Box 47, Folder 27)
    - Little Chino Valley, Standers well. 1937 (Box 47, Folder 28)
    - Little Chino Valley, Stuart windmill at Granite Creek. (Box 47, Folder 29)
    - Little Chino Valley, Watson Lake. 1939, 1965, 1968 (Box 47, Folder 30)
    - Little Chino Valley, views. 1966 (Box 47, Folder 31)
    - Little Chino Valley, Wells and pumps. 1967 (Box 47, Folder 32)
    - Little Chino Valley, Yarbro well. 1962 (Box 47, Folder 33)
    - Lonesome Valley. (Box 47, Folder 34)
    - Papago farms. (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Papago farms. 1928 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Papago farms. 1962 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Pima mine. (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Pinal County, consolidated mine. 1938 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Pinal County, Golder lake. (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Pinal County, Greene Canal. 1963 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Pinal County, Joe King farm. (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Pinal County, Old Waggoner house. (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Pinal County, Picacho Peak. (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Pinal County, Sasco. 1915 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Pinal County, Vertical displacement. (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Pinal County, Wells and pumps. 1962 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Prescott, wells and pumps. 1968 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - Sacaton Road. 1916 (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Sacaton well. 1919- (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Salt river. (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - Salton Sea. 1953 (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - San Pedro River, Gages. (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - San Pedro River, natural bridges. (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - San Xavier, cement pipe. 1938 (Box 48, Folder 21)
    - San Xavier, Diversion Dam. 1934-1935 (Box 48, Folder 22)
    - Santa Cruz river flood control. (Box 48, Folder 23)
    - Southwest Cotton Co. (Box 48, Folder 24)
    - St. David culverts. 1938 (Box 48, Folder 25)
    - Tucson Farmers' Co. (Box 48, Folder 26)
    - Universit of Arizona pipe. 1962 (Box 48, Folder 27)
    - Watson lake. (Box 48, Folder 28)
    - Adobe, forming and testing. (Box 48, Folder 29)
    - Adobe, house construction. (Box 48, Folder 30)
    - Agricultural engineers class photos. 1938-1939 (Box 48, Folder 31)
    - Bridge. (Box 48, Folder 32)
    - Canals. (Box 48, Folder 33)
    - Centrifugal pump tests. (Box 48, Folder 34)
    - Contour construction. (Box 48, Folder 35)
    - Dams, Sonoita. 1939 (Box 48, Folder 36)
    - Dams, unidentified. (Box 48, Folder 37)
    - Deep test well Tucson. 1964 (Box 48, Folder 38)
    - Drilling rigs, A.R.S. (Box 48, Folder 39)
    - Drilling rigs, Apache Powder Co. 1919 (Box 48, Folder 40)
    - Drilling rigs, Kerr McKee. 1963 (Box 48, Folder 41)
    - Fault-Catalina foothills. (Box 48, Folder 42)
    - Flood control outlets. (Box 48, Folder 43)
    - Floods and erosion, Alma dam. (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Floods and erosion, Benson/Pomerene dam. (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Floods and erosion, Catalina Mountains. (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Floods and erosion, Cholla, Catalina Mountains. (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Floods and erosion, Eloy. (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Floods and erosion, Gila camp. (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Floods and erosion, Green's Canal. (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Floods and erosion, Hassayampa river. 1943 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Floods and erosion, Laguna dam on Colorado. 1931-1932 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Floods and erosion, Marana. 1944-1950 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Floods and erosion, Pantano. (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Floods and erosion, Pima farms ditch. 1931 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Floods and erosion, Rillito river. 1935 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Floods and erosion, San Pedro. (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Floods and erosion, San Pedro at Curtis Dam. 1930-1933 (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - Floods and erosion, San Simon Valley. (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - Floods and erosion, San Xavier. (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - Floods and erosion, Santa Cruz River. 1914 (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - Floods and erosion, Santa Cruz river. 1914- (Box 49, Folder 19)
    - Floods and erosion, Santa Cruz river at Western Cotton Gin. 1939 (Box 49, Folder 20)
    - Floods and erosion, Santa Cruz river. 1955 (Box 49, Folder 21)
    - Floods and erosion, Santa Cruz river, Pinal County. 1962 (Box 49, Folder 22)
    - Floods and erosion, Santa Cruz river. 1963, 1965 (Box 49, Folder 23)
    - Floods and erosion, St. David ditch. 1930 (Box 49, Folder 24)
    - Floods and erosion, unidentified. (Box 49, Folder 25)
    - Gaging stations, Calco. 1920 (Box 49, Folder 26)
    - Gaging stations, general. (Box 49, Folder 27)
    - Irrigation, furrow. (Box 49, Folder 28)
    - Irrigation, general. (Box 49, Folder 29)
    - Irrigation, near border. (Box 49, Folder 30)
    - Pipe. (Box 49, Folder 31)
    - Pipe lines. (Box 49, Folder 32)
    - Power company. (Box 49, Folder 33)
    - Pump installation, Bill Thomas Ranch. (Box 49, Folder 34)
    - Pumping plants. (Box 49, Folder 35)
    - Pumping plants, Eloy. (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Pumps, Chino Valley. (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Pumps, general. (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Pumps, well testing. (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Rain collectors, De Grazia, Ted. 1958-1966 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Rain collectors, general. (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Rain collectors, Page ranch. (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Rain collectors, Vaca ranch. (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Recorders. (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - San simon Deep well rig. 1919 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Sprinkler fittings. (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Sprinkler irriation, Chino Valley. (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Untitled subjects. (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Well drilling. 1930s (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - Well drilling, Marana. (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Well drilling, San Pedro. (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - Well drilling, unknown rigs. (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - Well drilling, unknown rigs. (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Wells and pumps. (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - Wiers. (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - Wiers. (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - Contain charts and figures measuring flow of the San Pedro and Gila Rivers, (See Series 19) and charts for transpiration studies using Cottonwood, Mesquite, Sacaton, and Salt Grass wells, (See Series 20). 1928-1940, 1921-1925 (Box 51)
    - Contain charts and figures measuring flow of the San Pedro and Gila Rivers, (See Series 19) and charts for transpiration studies using Cottonwood, Mesquite, Sacaton, and Salt Grass wells, (See Series 20). 1928-1940, 1921-1925 (Box 52)